welcome to the listening Time Podcast
hey everybody this is Connor and you're
listening to
episode2 of the listening Time Podcast I
hope everybody's doing great uh I've
been traveling a lot recently and I'm
going to travel again today to be honest
I think it's been a little too much
traveling in a short period of time so
I'm excited for
uh this trip that I have but I'm also
excited that after this trip I'm
probably not going to travel for a while
and I'll just have a normal routine and
have a normal life I'm kind of looking
forward to having that for a little
while but I hope that some of you have
some interesting trips planned for maybe
this summer or this winter depending on
where you live which hemisphere you're
in uh hopefully you get the chance to do
some fun stuff or travel to some
interesting places this year and of
course I hope your English learning is
going well and if you're having trouble
understanding native speakers and you
need more help understanding fast speech
especially when native speakers reduce
sounds and say things in a way that's
very unclear or fast or
shortened then I encourage you to sign
up for my membership so that you can get
my specialized training where I help you
identify these different reductions and
sounds and patterns that will help you
become a little more comfortable with
fast speed speech so click on the link
in the episode description below this
episode to join my membership and you'll
get my listening practice seminars
you'll get that specialized training and
of course if you're a Spanish or a
Portuguese speaker you can get my ebook
my collection of three short stories
mystery stories uh that I wrote in
English and translated into Spanish and
into Portuguese so if you want to
practice reading fiction in English the
links to those are also in the episode
description all right today we're going
to talk about old age and I'll Focus
specifically on the US and what old age
is like in the US and maybe what life is
like for older people and things like
that so hopefully this will be an
interesting topic for for you and
remember that if you need the transcript
that's also in the description you can
go down there and click on that if you
need it and if you like this podcast
please share it with your friends and
your family members who could find it
useful people who are learning English
and please give it a fstar rating and
write a review all right let's get
started are your ears ready you you know
what time it is it's listening
time okay let's talk about old age so
first of all let's talk about how old
age is viewed in the US I think there
are a lot of mixed opinions when it
comes to this the phrase mixed opinions
refers to opinions that might be
contradictory
maybe some are positive some are
negative these are mixed opinions so
there are some
positive uh feelings when it comes to uh
old age and I think one of the main
positive things is that we tend to
associate old age with retirement with
being retired and not working anymore
and in the US retirement is seen
positively it's interesting because I
was talking with my wife about this
recently and we were comparing the
attitudes regarding retirement in the US
and in
Mexico and it's interesting because in
Mexico and probably in most countries
around the world um retirement isn't
necessarily seen as some amazing thing
right people don't have this idea that
they're going to have a fantastic life
once they're retired and they're going
to do tons of fun activities and travel
around the world and all that kind of
stuff however often times Americans kind
of Fant ize about retirement we uh
romanticize it a little bit uh we uh
tend to think that this will be a great
time in our lives and people often
prepare very hard uh for many years for
retirement and once they're retired they
try to have fun and just enjoy their
life uh to the max so many retired
people like to travel to many places and
take up new hobbies and uh find fun
things to do by the way in English we
can use the phrasal verb take up when
referring to starting a hobby so for
example if if I say I took up tennis
that just means that I started this
hobby so older people when they're
retired they often take up new hobbies
and try to do a lot of fun activities so
in that sense this part of old age can
definitely be seen positively in the US
however there are also some negative
feelings when when it comes to old age
because in the US just like everywhere
else in the world older people tend to
have more health problems so there are
often aches and pains that people have
to deal with uh in English the word ache
refers to a pain that you have for
example if I say I have a headache I'm
saying that I have pain in my head so
when you get older you tend to have more
aches and pains your body doesn't feel
the same uh as it felt when you were
younger and you might have some more
serious health conditions you might have
health conditions that don't allow you
to um have this really active
lifestyle so we never know uh what our
health will be like when we're older and
so that can cause maybe some fear uh
when it comes to getting older so as you
can see there are some mixed opinions uh
mixed
feelings uh because on the one hand when
you get older and you
retire uh in the US you can often have a
lot of fun but but on the other hand
your body might not be in the best shape
to have all of this fun so uh it's not
completely positive or completely
negative in terms of my view uh and how
I view old age I think that um there are
positives and negatives of course and I
think my advice to myself would be to
try to do well now in order to reap the
benefits later in English when we say
that you reap benefits we're saying that
you receive the benefits of uh something
that you do now and you reap those
benefits you receive them at a later
time usually so this can be applied to
your body if you take care of your body
when you're younger then hopefully
you'll have a better body in the future
and if you take care of your mind when
you're younger uh hopefully you'll be in
good mental health in the future and if
you focus on your relationships when
you're younger hopefully you'll have
good relationships in the future when
you're older and you'll have uh a good
circle of people people around you that
are willing to help you in case you need
help and uh who you can connect with at
that age so hopefully I'm able to do
those things next let's talk a little
bit about the living situation of older
people in the US so in the US older
people tend to try to be as independent
as possible POS for as long as possible
this is just part of our culture we are
uh more independent than other cultures
and people really value being able to
take care of
themselves uh most people uh don't
really want other people to take care of
them right uh people here want to take
care of themselves feel independent feel
in control of their own life that's one
of the cultural elements here so that
also tends to apply to a lot of older
people uh they want to hold on to their
independence as long as possible so it's
quite common for people here to continue
living on their own even when they're a
little bit older
right if people are 80 years old but
they're in great health and they don't
need any help with their daily lives
it's possible that they might live alone
even if they're 80 years old um of
course the older you get um the more
likely it is that you'll need some help
right but people in their 70s and even
people in their 880s might still be very
independent and might be able to do
everything um for themselves so if they
can they tend to do that however uh
sometimes they decide to go to a
retirement community these are
communities uh or residential buildings
that are uh designed for seniors by the
way we can use the word senior to uh
talk about an older person so these
communities are intended for seniors who
can still take care of themselves mostly
but um they might have very easy access
to help or care if they need it in these
communities so uh they live among other
older people there and they probably
have a lot of activities and social
events and uh things like that uh and
they have easy access to help if they
need it but they can still live
independently for the most part so we
have those retirement communities and a
lot of people um like those types of
communities when they're older because
it really provides a lot of uh
socializing and things like that and if
people need a little bit more assistance
if they need a little more help with uh
their daily tasks uh their daily life
maybe their health then they might live
in an assisted living facility um this
is a place uh where people who aren't
completely
independent uh might live and they
receive some help um they receive more
help than in a retirement community for
example so they'll probably have daily
help with their tasks um health issues
things like that but they can still be
somewhat independent and try to do a lot
of things on their own in this place but
if the person really can't take care of
themselves uh and they really need uh
someone else to take care of them and
help them out then they often go to live
in a nursing home uh and in a nursing
home you have all the help that you need
someone is always there to provide you
with whatever
assistance is
necessary um that is uh kind of a
longterm Care Facility we might call it
so you uh receive everything that you
need in order to uh live your daily life
and you have all the help that you might
want uh so that's for people that really
can't take care of themselves anymore so
those are some different living
situations that people might have once
they reach an older age so how about
living with your kids or your grandkids
when you're older well this isn't that
common in the US it happens some people
do this but it's definitely not as
common as it is in many other countries
around the world for example in Mexico
this is really common a lot of
grandparents uh live with their children
and their
grandchildren uh especially if one of
the grandparents has passed away uh for
example if the grandfather is no longer
alive it's very common for the
grandmother to live uh with her children
and her
grandchildren so that's common in many
countries
however in the US it's not as common
when I was growing up I remember that I
had some friends who had this living
situation their grandparents lived with
them but practically all of these
friends that had this were children of
immigrants so their parents and their
grandparents were from other countries
and in their countries this was normal
so I can't really remember having
friends who weren't the children of
immigrants who had this type of living
situation so that should show you that
it's not that common here again people
do this and some people uh they like
this but I would say that it's not the
norm here by the way in English we can
say that something is the
norm uh when we want to say that it's
normal or it's the normal thing to do so
that's not the norm here however me
personally I tend to like the idea of
having your parents uh live with you uh
when they get too old to take care of
themselves uh that's something that I
have always offered uh to my parents um
if they need to live with us then I
think that they should I think that if
it's possible uh that would be a nice
thing uh to be able to do for my parents
since they took care of me uh all
throughout my childhood so I like that
idea but I would say that many other
people might not like that idea and so
that really just depends on your own
personality your own
preferences um not everyone would agree
with that but that's kind of my opinion
and lastly let's talk about some
activities that older people might do so
in the US older people are encouraged to
take care of their health and um older
people tend to be conscious that they
need
to exercise and keep their body in shape
and so it's really common to see older
people walking early in the morning or
at different times during the day but uh
I tend to walk pretty early in the
morning uh I like walking and I see
almost almost exclusively older people I
don't really see a lot of younger people
walking around the neighborhood at this
time and that's because younger people
tend to uh have to work or go to school
or whatever but you get my point I see a
lot of older people walking around the
neighborhood uh pretty early in the
morning and they do this in groups
sometimes s or they might do it with
their spouse um but that's very common
and it's common for them to um try to
engage in light exercise so they might
have some exercise classes or uh
programs um it just depends on U their
preference and there are some sports
that older people
really like in the US um I would say the
most popular sport for um seniors in the
US is golf uh I love golf I haven't
played in years but I still love this
Sport and I hope to take it up again in
the future uh but if you play golf in
the US you notice that uh there are a
lot of of older people playing on the
course so this sport is not very hard on
your body so I think that's why uh it's
a great uh type of sport for older
people and I sometimes see older people
playing tennis too uh tennis is
definitely harder on your body than golf
you definitely have to move more but I
think that a lot of older people can
also play tennis and enjoy this Sport
and I'm sure there are plenty of other
sports uh that would be good options for
seniors as well and some older people
like to Garden uh they might uh try to
take really good care of uh their Garden
or their front yard or their backyard
and that can be a good activity for
people um and it can be something that
is even a little bit therapeutic for
people a lot of people like to Garden
because it's good for their mind so that
can be a great activity for older people
and of course if they can older people
tend to like to travel as I mentioned uh
people want once they
retire sometimes uh want to travel as
much as possible with all of their free
time so that's another great activity
and of course one other very common
activity is spending time with
grandchildren that's obviously something
that a lot of grandparents really like
to do all right why don't we stop there
for today I hope this episode was
interesting for you remember that you
have the transcript available if you
need it and if you want to practice with
the difficult sounds of English and you
need help understanding native speakers
when they speak fast make sure to become
a listening time member so that you can
access my listening practice seminars
and start to understand those Concepts
uh those patterns a little bit better
so you can click on the link in the
description to access those that's
patreon.com listening time and of course
if you're a Spanish or a Portuguese
speaker then check out my ebook to start
reading fiction in English all right
thank you for listening to this episode
and I'll talk to you on the next episode
of listening
[Music]
time